A Guide to the National Committee on United States-China Relations records, RG 8, Accession 8 FA1190
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Board of Directors, Committees, and Members records, 1958, 1965-2014; 11
  - Former Members ( C ) (Box 36, Folder 283)
    Chabut, David, 1996-2000; Cho, Morley L., 1991-1995; Creel, Jane, 1976-2007, 2012.
  - Former Members (D - G) (Box 36, Folder 284)
    Daley, William M., 2001-2007, 2013; Fuller, William P., IV, 1996-2005, 2011; Geyer, Alan, 1967, 1977-2003, 2012 (note on folder indicates that a file of earlier material is missing).
  - Former Members: Heggie, Richard, 1971-2007; 2012 (Box 36, Folder 285)
  - Former Members: Holbrooke, Richard C. A., 1985-2010 (Box 36, Folder 286)
  - Former Members: Holland - Jeremiah, Still Image: 8x10 color print. (Box 36, Folder 287)
    Holland, Clifford, 2008, 2014 (resigned); Jeremiah, David E., 1994-2009. File includes color portrait of Jeremiah.
  - Former Members: Kallgren, Joyce K., 1973-2008; 2013 (Box 37, Folder 288)
  - Former Members: Karp, Irving J., 1975-2009 (Box 37, Folder 289)
  - Former Members: Kwong, Daniel W., 1995-2011 (Box 37, Folder 290)
  - Former Members (L - R) (Box 37, Folder 291)
    Martin, G. Eugene, 2001-2011 (deceased); Richardson, General William R., 1995-2002, 2012; Rosenson, Harriet, 1984-2012.
  - Former Members: Schlesinger, James R., 1982; 1996-2007; 2014 (Box 37, Folder 292)
  - Former Members: Tucker, Nancy Bernkopf, 1988-2012 (Box 37, Folder 293)
    Includes one item relating to Joseph Tucker, 2008.
  - Former Members (U - Z) (Box 37, Folder 294)
    Wachman, Alan A., 1996-2012; Whittemore, Laurence F., 1982-2008.
- NCUSCR Presidents' Files, 1997-2004; 14
  Douglas P. Murray served as president pro tem of the National Committee from December 1997 through August 1998, succeeding David M. Lampton. John L. Holden was president from September 1998 through 2005. The Presidents Files include chronological files and correspondence. Files are lacking for the last portion of John Holden's term.
  - Douglas P. Murray Chronological Files, 1997 December - 1998 August (Box 37, Folder 295)
  - John L. Holden Chronological Files, 1998 September - 1999 July (Box 37, Folder 296-297)
    File for July -December 1999 includes material relating to ACS merger with the NCUSCR.
  - John L. Holden Chronological Files, 1999 August - 2002 (Box 38, Folder 298-304)
  - John L. Holden Chronological Files, 2003- 2004 July (Box 39, Folder 305-307)
  - John L. Holden Chronological Files, 2003 June - December (Box 39, Folder 306A)
  - John L. Holden Correspondence, 2000 October - 2002 October (Box 39, Folder 308-309)
    Includes some incoming as well as outgoing correspondence.
  - John L. Holden Speeches, Articles, and Press Appearances, 1999-2001; 2002-2003 (Box 39, Folder 310-311)
- Clippings and Reference, 1968-1987; 15
  - Issues: Normalization, 1972-1986 (Box 40, Folder 312-315)
    Includes draft of Steven M. Goldstein and Jay Mathews, "Sino-American Relations after Normalization: Toward the Second Decade," circa 1986.
  - Normalization: Pre - December 1978 Editorials, 1972-1978 (Box 40, Folder 316)
  - United States - PRC - Taiwan (Political), 1978-1986 (Box 40, Folder 317)
  - United States - PRC - Taiwan (Weapons Sale to Taiwan), 1981-1984 (Box 40, Folder 318)
  - PRC - Canada, 1972-1986 (Box 40, Folder 319)
  - PRC - Asia Relations (General), 1974-1987 (Box 40, Folder 320)
  - PRC - Australasia Relations (Oceana, Australia, New Zealand), 1971-1986 (Box 40, Folder 321)
  - PRC - Bangladesh, 1975-1977 (Box 40, Folder 322)
  - PRC - Burma, Laos, Thailand, Nepal, 1970-1985 (Box 41, Folder 323)
  - PRC - Hong Kong and Macao, 1970-1987 (Box 41, Folder 324-325)
  - Hong Kong, 1981-1986 (Box 41, Folder 326)
  - PRC - India, 1974-1985 (Box 41, Folder 327)
  - PRC - Indonesia, 1973-1985 (Box 41, Folder 328)
  - PRC - Japan (Non-Economic Issues), 1971-1987 (Box 41, Folder 329)
  - PRC - Japan (Economic Issues), 1971-1986 (Box 41, Folder 330)
  - PRC - Korea, 1971-1987 (Box 42, Folder 331)
  - PRC - Pakistan and Afghanistan, 1972-1985 (Box 42, Folder 332)
  - PRC - Philippines, 1973-1986 (Box 42, Folder 333)
  - PRC - Singapore and Malaysia, 1974-1984 (Box 42, Folder 334)
  - PRC - Kampuchea and Vietnam (Press Releases), 1970-1983 (Box 42, Folder 335)
    File consists mainly of Press Releases from the PRC Mission to the United Nations, 1973-1979.
  - PRC - Kampuchea and Vietnam, 1972-1987 (Box 42, Folder 336-337)
  - Vietnam - China Confrontations, 1979-1986 (Box 42, Folder 338)
  - PRC - U.S.S.R. (Technological and Economic Relations), 1968-1986 (Box 42, Folder 339)
  - PRC - United States - U. S. S. R. (Political and Military Issues), 1973-1984 (Box 42, Folder 340)
    File consists mainly of Press Releases from the PRC Mission to the United Nations, 1973-1977.
  - PRC - Non-Aligned Movement and United Nations, 1979-1983 (Box 42, Folder 341)